[Music] welcome to my journey through the
enchanting Kingdom of Bhutan this remote
Himalayan country remains a Hidden Gem to many
Travelers but offers a amazing experience for
those who can make it here over the next 2 hours
I'll be taking you to the landmarks across Bhutan
and exploring everything from dramatic cliffsides
temples to bustling Village markets to the warm
Hospitality of the people so nice they're going
so out of their way so kind for international
viewers get ready to discover bhutan's stunning
natural sites relaxing Buddhist culture and their
sustainable way of life you'll see why it is
called the land of happiness and for my bhese
friends watching I hope you enjoy revisiting
some of your country's top destinations and
reimmerse yourself back in the culture let's
celebrate the beauty traditions and spirit
of your amazing Homeland together the adventure
begins now hello vhan wow okay so we've officially
landed in Bon wo all [Music] [Applause] [Music]
right amazing what an entrance this is wow from
the heart racing Landing through the clouds
Landing in the world's most dangerous airport
we now get our first taste of bhutan's striking
natural beauty oh my gosh the airport is like
a temple right I got to stop filming now it's
very quiet Sophia all good so good wow you got
treated nice yeah did you just say I want to cry
why because it's so beautiful it's so beautiful
a you're tearing up yeah a a little even the
baggage car cell looks [Music] beautiful so
we're just getting a SIM card right now for
1,50 and that's unlimited data for 7 days so
that should be good we'll just get one sim card
and then Sophia and I can share through [Music]
Hotpot
[Music]
what's your name uh t t yes Jack nice to meet
you yes lovely to meet you and Sophia okay so
we're now in the van it is so hot here online
it said it' be like 16° but it is hot is hot
yeah our guide was just saying that it's due
to global warming the temperatures been on and
off here it's been crazy um so we've got some
water sitting back relaxing and we're going to
go and look at the traditional dress now the
what's it called go go and go and Kira and
yeah and then we're going to be eating some
lunch and exploring it just feels so good
to be here it's uh absolutely beautiful
wow Bhutan is so beautiful thank you so
[Music] wow [Music] your country is so nice
Okay so we've just arrived to a store to get
the CO and Kira so this is Kira and this is
go and go okay cool for Kira it's very easy
because they have made it like a hook system
so you just wrap it around it's very easy oh
wow that is easy yeah the people here are so
helpful they're trying to get me a bigger size
as well and making sure I'm okay the hospitality
here is crazy we're very lucky wow very nice egg
rambro I just took off my pants so it's a
little bit it's a little bit cooler that's
how they wear it here because uh yeah
it gets very hot so I just took off my
pants and the breeze is very nice I have
to say and sopia looks very pretty thank
you wow I feel so loved in this country
everyone's so nice right so nice like
going so out of their way so kind wow here
we go we've got some people here taking some
[Music]
photos what's the population here so it is
about uh uh 7 lakhs 7 lakhs yes okay so uh
700 uh 700,000 700,000 okay country is the
only carbon negative country right yes wow
that's insane so could you tell us a little bit
more about what that means so carbon negative
means like we produce uh like more oxygen than
we produce carbon carbon wow so that's why like
we have other countries like India who produce
more carbon and our countries like try to cover
up all this to keep keep up with this title so our
government has a policy uh which means that like
the 70% of the forest should remain like of the
country should remain as a forest so how's that
70% of the country is covered in natural Forest
that is insane when you think about it wow and
this is like one of the greenest times right
like everything is so green yeah wow [Music]
and he had built around 108 uh like Iron Bridge
over the like uh Tibet and inutan so this is one
of the wow so he built that yes what was his name
uh Tang that is awesome isn't it and how old is
this um Temple yeah 15th century 15th century
oh my goodness [Music] wow okay so we're going
to go down and check out this uh Bridge here so
this was built in the 15th century wow this is so
cool so we're going to to go across now the
rebuilt bridge now this one here is from the
15th century the reason why it's locked is so
people don't steal it so we're just going to go
across this one here it's a little bit wobbly
but you can see here how fast these Rapids
are oh my gosh I would not want to fall down
in here let me tell you wow he so we've just
arrived at this lovely local Resort here for
lunch so uh yeah let's go and see C is shall
we Cheers Cheers he just asked me if I wanted
anything else from the menu they've already
made lunch for us and then and he said do you
want anything else from the menu so I got some
seasonal fruit and he said oh no worries and he
said do you want some fresh juice as well and I
said yeah so guys now might be a good time to
explain what's going on here so this is a very
expensive restaurant obviously um and something
that's not usually in my budget of videos but
I'm actually here with the government of Bhutan
yes that's right jack T got a very good sponsor
um so yeah we're here with the government and
uh we're promoting bhan and in return they're
offering us a trip and uh yeah we're going to be
not just in amazing highend places like this but
we'll also be in villages in local places as well
talking to the people so don't worry it's not all
going to be Glamour and amazing stuff but this
is quite a shock for us isn't it right [Music]
yeah everything is so nice in here
here even the AC unit has a cover on
it chicken Momo chicken Momo okay cool I'm
so excited for this yeah so oh wow our uh
our what are what are these called again go
Joe Co our Coes look the same we're 20 yes
wow thank you wow so we've got the chicken
Momo here let's give this a taste little bit
of chili sauce little bit of garlic Mayo all
right I think this is going to be hot let's
see it's pretty good right oh you doing a Momo
dance good [Music] Momo after seeing bhutan's
incredible Landscapes and getting a taste for
their food it's time to meet the friendly people
The bhones Pride themselves on the concept of
gross national happiness or g&h for short you can
feel their warm and welcoming Spirit as I visit a
local Cultural Center their smiles are infectious
you will [Music] say and we're about to get a tour
and explain some different things so let's see
and welcome to sim bhan so now ma'am sir I will
Ser you our welcome drink so it's our culture to
welcome a guest with a local wine so whenever the
guest visit a house we welcome them with the local
wine so we called it ARA in our language how you
say it ARA yes ARA okay nice fermented wine okay
lovely cheers it's okay Cheers Cheers
how it m say you like it oh yeah it's lovely
so good yeah I would love some more [Music]
place this red one use it as a belt for
the leader of the cattle so when Seasons
get changed the cattles will migrate from
one place to another so while migrating the
leader of the cattle will wear this belt and
they will lead the way of other cattles and
this one is backpack it's made out of yak
skin oh wow Yak skin yes wow oh wow very
[Music]
nice
Divine madman or the C oh okay
so so these aren't mushrooms okay
okay
all seriousness though that's really cool I mean
if if that works then that's great really cool I
yeah no problem it's really cool that isal bunis
kitchen so in the olden days we don't have proper
ventilation system so that's what we have this
type of chimneys for the ventilation and then you
can also see the color of the wall it's black in
colors it's all because of the smoke so the smoke
will also keep your house warm in the olden days
and then you can see this small ball over here so
it's made out of out and inside we have a SC so
whenever the temperature get increased it will
get l so that it can War a person from getting
fired wow nice do you want to drink a cup of
[Music] tea okay so we're now in this little
room here we been serve some tea and then I
believe there's going to be a folk dance
as well um this section here is a little
bit touristy but this is really cool
to see how Bhutan was like 100 years
ago so right now I'm about to try some
butter tea so let's give this a try shall
we oh yeah M oh got a dance
coming
[Music]
hello how are you this man here he's very
famous in bhan uh his condition is cble Cy
and the Queen Mother actually went to adopt
him when she adopted him she said to him what
do you want money gold and he chose education
and what they could find is that he could use
his feet really well so now he's got education
to do wood carvings which is absolutely amazing
he's very famous here in B time so yeah
really cool to me this guy in person wow
very nice so good so many tools as well yeah
awesome we've got one of these carvings here
that he's done as well so cool look at the
details yeah the details are crazy wow byebye
byby [Music] w [Music]
[Music]
what is
this hey hey good job
no there you go [Music]
no so we've now arrived at our hotel as
well I'm going to be giving you guys a
tour of this place and they've also got some
things installed for us I believe hot stone
baths massages so we should see how that is I'm
very excited wow your thank Youk lovely cold
to lovely so guys I am very excited to um
show you the room here and show you some of
the facility is what hotels can get you here in
Bhutan I believe it's really good let's see um'
got amazing artwork here in the foyer so we're
on the top floor I'm so excited are you too
okay so we've just checked into our five-star
hotel here at Nill Boutique Hotel and Spa let
me tell you this room is absolutely amazing and
it has and it has some of the best views of the
city come and check this out so we've got a
amazing bed just here and then also a work
desk as well it's very very nice we can get
a lot of work done over here we've also got
a welcome cake we've got a lovely couch over
here sit back relax but this is the best part
this is the best part look at this check out
this view wow so now that we've wet our feet
in our first aame Bhutan and experienced some
of our first impressions it's now time to take
on a whirlwind whole day exploring bhutan's
capital city of tempo the nation's largest
city manages to balance modernization and also
its traditional charms from the Lively markets
to the government buildings join me as I
try to pack it all in to one busy [Music]
day so I tell you what so far Bhutan has been
absolutely amazing my expectations are just
through the roof it's been so nice the hospitality
here is amazing our guides are so friendly even
the people in the street are so friendly willing
to talk to you say hello it's such a beautiful
country the air is so fresh 70% of this country
is covered in natural Forest which makes it the
only country in the world with a negative CO2
emissions yeah I tell you what we are so blessed
to be here what an opportunity it is to share
this country with you guys so right now we're
on the second level of the Buddha and as always
we're going right and shoulder around uh I don't
know what happens if you go the other way but I
don't think it's good so a little bit of history
on this Buddha here it was meant to be finished
in 2006 but due to unforeseen circumstances it
actually finished in 2015 now the Chinese actually
sponsored uh this to be built which is very nice
of them and I believe Taiwan also helped with
that as well so yeah really really lovely an
absolute icon IC Landmark here in Bhutan that's
for sure so they do perform some teaching out
here so this is the place that you see this the
place where they give teachings and like it will
go up to like 3 months 4 months till 6 months
and people from all over the country they come
here they they get teaching they Camp their
house here and they started living here for 6
months they get teaching and they got go back so
right now we're actually getting a exclusive look
of the fat tree down at the bottom of the Buddha
point where they make the Buddha statue so we had
to ask for permission to even look at this a lot
of people cannot come here so here's an exclusive
for you guys so we're in the factory right now so
this is the B head that they'll put into this and
everyone here is actually napoi fun fact wow so
this is some of the work that I've done behind
me [Music] the all of the Napo workers
in there yeah yeah so how did they come
about to get this this work so like there's a
royal project Happening Here Yeah and uh just
to work here yeah yeah and that's why they can
live in like this temporary housing right yeah
yeah okay cool thanks okay wow so how cool
is that getting an exclusive look into how
they make the Buddha statues so good absolutely
amazing you wouldn't think that that was there
just walking past like all the workers were
inside so right now what we're going to do
is we're going to go to the incent um Factory
where they make incent and uh it's actually
a special type of incent and a lot of people
especially tourists coming from from Singapore
and China actually buy these incent and take
it back home because I believe here is a lot
better and we'll find out why soon [Music] enough
thank [Music] you so the government schools here
are better than the private schools yes even
our King St he study in government School wow
our King study in government School wow are the
government schools free yes wow free education
in Bhutan like in other parts of Bhutan there are
Central School where like everything is provided
like food the clothing the book everything
is provided wow they will pay for [Music]
everything [Music]
so we're just in the uh tourism office of the
tour company that we're with and we're meeting
the manager I really like your office it's very
nice oh yeah yeah thank you so much for helping
curate uh everything that we've done this cucumber
is from Bhutan from our vegetable market probably
you'll go down Bhutan organic cucumber wow want
you to try this one wow really good right nice
wow I was wondering if you could explain j& H
to me and what that stands for and what Bhutan
does in regards to that but the experts they have
the they have the keys how to measure the GMS you
know in different labels the most important
is the culture that we have the family bond
in bhan is very very strong we look after our
Elder Generations uh very uh respectfully one
important thing that I found including myself
I always goes uh back to my Village once in a
year to meet my families to uh to perform my
family Puja which is very very important that
is annual ritual and one final question if you
were to name just three things that make you
happy in your life what would they be as I said
uh first first of all being in Bhutan visiting
Bhutan at at every Countryside I would love
to visit another one is uh being a bines I'm
always proud always proud be being bues because
uh being a bues is something very different you
know so I'm I'm very privileged to be born in
ban you amazing thank you so [Music] much [Music]
okay so we just left the office there and
after speaking to the CEO with Mercury
travels Bhutan what an amazing guy
uh explaining J&H and gross national
happiness Okay so we've now just arrived here
at the zoo we're here to see the goat cow deer
looking thing let's go and see that and see what
other animals they have they might have tigers
and bears I like your hair by the way I didn't
know that you had dreadlocks oh yeah it's newly
done good okay but this animal it's actually like
even they were set free they were like actually
like coming to the town area and they were like
always in theia there is one just here eating so
you guys are going to see this you're going to
be very amazed because this animal looks very
very different compared to most animals I've ever
seen in my life so yeah let's have a look hello
talkim hello talk hello hello wow he's a big boy
you're a big boy a big boy so yeah a little bit
hard to see through the fence but this right
here is what they call a tuck him which is
cross between the bottom is like a cow body
and the top is more like a goat right a goat
yeah so yeah really cool why are you saying meow
to it it's not a cat he's cute he sleeping over
there but this big boy here wow so they're built
like this because they're they were originally up
in the mountains right yes usually they are in
himalay but like this one they are like always
around this area I see and then that's why it
was okay to make the zoo because they're used
to the climate and the ground and everything and
do you know what these deers they have all come
from the forest to this area and the some some
they were found in the town area and just in
order to protect them they have put it here wow
and he's eating a big stick too aren't you H big
stick
[Music]
oh hey okay bye kids here are so
[Applause] [Laughter]
cheaky second time thank you oh he did it
that's nice Ah that's nice I love [Music]
you you're wear you're doing ballerina
feet your feet why are you walking like
that your feet are turned inside out
buddy okay so right now we're just
leaving the zoo and we're actually going
on a little uh Forest walk so apparently
it's really really beautiful walk so let's
see what we can find this is what it's all
about being in nature getting out of the
city experiencing the real Bhutan right
here [Music]
kro you've picked up this rubbish oh why because
it was want some people have so there was a piece
of rubbish in the ground this is how amazing
the botines people are and chro our guide has
just picked it up without saying anything and
yeah just cleaning up their country making it
clean oh mushroom yeah wow could we eat
that or no no oh okay why we might get a
little bit magical if we eat those ones magic
mushrooms so what what were you just saying to
me so people really say that Bhutan and Nepal
are quite similar but what I think like in my
perspective is it has a little touch of Nepal
but I think bhan is like completely different
and nepales people should really really come
here and experience this country it's lovely
I totally agree even though Sophia has lived
in Nepal her whole life I've probably spent 6
months there and I can tell you it's completely
different there are some similarities just like
Nepal and India but different right so
different you definitely have to come
here so right now we've just finished up
that walk here and we're going to go and
eat some lunch which I'm really
excited for so yeah let's [Music]
go
[Music] Okay so we've just made it into the
market here at Kaja H so we're going to see
[Music]
what fruits and vegetables are being sold
here now all the fruits and vegetables come
from the village so this is super Super
Fresh and very very local I don't think
many of the fruits here are actually
imported so yeah let's go and check it
[Music]
out [Music] so this fruit market
looks like it goes on and on and
on as far as I can see I just see fruit and
vegetables so they also have a lot of spices
and chilies here as well so they've got
the traditional dried out chili so they
pick it and hang it up and it gets dried
out also got onions here tomatoes lettuce
what is it tber t what's that bamboo Sho
how much is the small honey honey uh caty
1500 uh I'll get one one honey
honey El uh uh Ela yes honey
Ela nice to meet you nice to meet
you
life's so simple here for these kids
no iPad no iPhone just a crate that
was once full of vegetables I love that
so this little girl here is also wearing
a Kira which is the same as what Sophie
is wearing the traditional dress so yeah
they start the kids off very young here wearing
the traditional stuff so cute wow wa [Applause]
hello hey thanks who hello hi hey who's that
what's your name this isim mimo wow wow nice
nice you're so tired wow s wow go oh oh come
on okay okay come on wao say like And subscribe
subscribe subscribe yeah nice oh wow big muscles
wow wo nice muscles Bhutan is famous for its
cheese and butter right yes wow all the curry
we put all the curry you put in this one cheese
cheese and butter do you like cheese and butter as
well um do you like chees no no oh okay worry less
chill more yeah yeah nice Duck Duck Donald Duck
yeah wow what's your shirt Puma wow to subscribe
yes subscribe nice wow high five hey to subscribe
yeah yeah I think you're the coolest kid in bhan
I have oh wow yeah look you have cool shoes wow
you're the I think you're the coolest kid you're
the best kid in bhan right yeah so we need to
subscribe subscribe yeah awesome subscribe yeah
okay cool we'll get many subscribers ready hey
nice you know this one hey see you later bye bye
bye subscribe and sub and see there we go that's
how important it is to get your kids off the phone
those two kids are laughing and playing this kid
is you know in another world so yeah I'm going to
try my vest with my children but let's see it's
not easy Okay so we've just walked into to the
zong here where the monks were learning English
now we weren't allowed to film inside but we
just got this clip here of one of the young boys
always um saying what he likes so yeah the um the
architecture here is something that just blows my
mind this was built in the 16th centures the 1600s
and for the fact that it was so big is absolutely
crazy now this was originally a fortress and then
it was later once the recent kings came in it
was recently turned into a monk Monastery this
was once a fortress this is the first and smallest
Fortress in all of bhan so we'll be seeing some
other fortresses in this series in Bhutan this one
is especially special because this is the first
and smallest so yeah this is absolutely amazing
and also down here as you can see there's like a
window so that's also other classrooms and stuff
and as you can see here behind me this is actually
an image that represents something really special
and it's all different animals of different kinds
working together to pick this fruit and it sort of
symbolizes that many people in the world where all
all different right you have the elephant you
have the monkey you have people from different
cultures different religions different countries
and it's important to always work together so it
just sort of shows the harmony of working
together and it's really really lovely and
also just here behind me is actually where the
monks stay now they don't stay in the Fortress
because that's where they do most of their study
and learning but here is where all of them stay
and this building was actually built around the
same time in the 1600s so this building is very
old wow so it used to be that one person from
every family had to be a monk yes but now it's
just by choice right yes by choice I see and uh
once they finish their studies they can choose to
leave and live normal life or stay to be a monkey
so yes it depends on their [Music] choices so in
we have the it's a knife so this tool here is
called Zena and it's used for like stirring
the rice and mixing the rice when you're cooking
it it's really cool so this man here he sells uh
different types of cooking utensils and also
knives as well now sometimes he'll only sell
One in Every 3 days sometimes he'll sell three in
one day it sort of just depends the businesses up
and down just like everything but yeah he's got
a good little business here and like the other
people that we were talking about he's on the
outside of the market so I don't believe he's
paying rent for this so his costs are down as
well so now we've just came to a Thor slide chule
there's many names for these shoes but this is a
retail market so you can get all different types
of choules here yeah all different types of Croc
slides so it's very popular especially in South
Asia so we were just learning about the different
number plates here right so if we look down here
this is actually actually BP which stands for
Bhutan private but if we look at this taxi over
here it says BT which stands for Bhutan taxi now
if it's a government vehicle it will be BG Bhutan
government so yeah it's sort of interesting isn't
it that each of the number plates are registered
based on what the vehicle is used for so yeah
very fascinating also one quick note I love the
architecture here in Bhutan it's so nice it sort
of reminds me the closest thing it reminds me to
is like an old Japan in a way like a little bit
but it's still completely unique is being a taxi
driver a good job it's okay it's okay it's good
and what's the best part about his job because
we getting uh we are going anywhere if there no
we didn't reach anywhere we reaching yet amazing
that means he get to travel with the passenger
and he get to see lots of other places where he
had not been wow yeah so what makes you happy
like family any landscape friends our climate
is very good anywhere nice oxygen to breathe in
yeah good good nature okay awesome thank you so
much thank you for your [Music] time now we're
at the waving Center uh so yeah this is where
they do traditional waving and make the co and
uh Kira so let's go in and have a look so this
is the traditional w leaving Center so yeah
they they make pretty much what sop far and
I are wearing right now but handmade not in a
factory so this is really really interesting
one year to complete one yes making wow so
it' be very expensive to buy right yes yeah
wow that's insane these people are so talented
though looks very tricky how long does it take
to learn how to do this so from the childhood
she been like learning a little bit little bit
and now she's exper wow so maybe like 3 years
to be a pro yes more than that I guess [Music]
wow so how can you tell the difference between
hand uh waved and fatory for hand weaving sir
you'll find this kind uh at backside you'll
find this kind M for mechine M it will be
fine very fine and smooth and shiny too but
uh for hand weaving it will be little thicker
and little rough the queen wore this one how
cool is that so uh yeah when The Royal Wedding
happened the uh the dress that she wore is up
here on this wall that the queen wore that is
absolutely amazing with purification the king
and his bride moved out of sight to a sacred
Shrine room where their Union was blessed by the
king father as had been planned this was a very
public affirmation of bhutan's tradition
and culture something it's determined to
protect as a modern world encroaches ever
more this is what a uh hand weav uh store
looks like here in bhan and as we could see
that the lowest price was about $60 goes all
the way up to $8,000 for the co and Kira much I
love it 950 wow it's a good price yeah egg rro
lovely you going to wear it in Nepal wow nice so
we just leaving the traditional weaving shop now
but I just wanted to point out all of these flags
here so this is when someone passes away they put
up 108 Flags uh in their memory and it's sort of
a spiritual and cultural thing and after about a
year's time they'll come and remove them you know
their Spirit uh waves in the wind but yeah it's
very interesting [Music] after the hustle and
bustle of tempo we slow way down for a peaceful
24 hours in rural ban life definitely moves
at a different pace here in the countryside I
help farmers with their daily tasks try some
delicious homecooked meals and even try my
hand at milking a cow so yeah let's go roads
here in Bhutan are really really well looked
after so right now we're sort of on I guess you
could say the highway to pinaka but um it's not
really straight it's very curvy because it goes
in between the mountains so so far and I aren't
really used to this so we've just stopped off
on the side of the road this beautiful little
sh try here with all these prayer flags and the
water coming out so yeah just from the running
water this prayer wheel just spins and Spins
constantly and it's also became really really
foggy as well as you can see so the temperature
has dropped a little bit so today we're going
from Tempo all the way up very cold then back
down into hotter environment let's get back in
the car now and uh continue our journey the fog
is so thick this is a little bit scary are you
like on yes okay good oh you can't see anything
it's crazy like it's 10:00 and the fog is still
really really thick so do you think maybe like
3 or 4 it would clear or still the same yeah
like the same wow 2,100 m 3,1 3,100 m wow that's
crazy no wonder there's so much fog so a quick
5 minute drive up the road we are now at do ster
and there's 108 sters here uh this place is very
very famous but as you can see we're in the
fog but uh yeah this is really really [Music]
[Music]
lovely these sters have a super interesting
history behind them the reason why they're
here is because in the 2003 Civil War a
lot of soldiers died and they actually
built these 108 Troopers to remember them now
no 108 soldiers didn't die it was much more
than that but 108 is a uh superstitious
number in Buddhism like a good number
for that reason they built 108 striopers now
in each stooper they have some type of Jewel
or something that remembers the soldiers
some significant artifact so yeah it's
really really amazing and then at the middle
of all the sters they have the very big [Music]
stoer so we''ve just stopped off in the there
all these wild monkeys here got to be careful
that they don't jump in the car hello hi Monkey
how cool is that these guys look so friendly too
they're not violent or anything they're not
intimidated they're just curious wow lovely
monkeys in Bhutan normally they're really violent
right oh look this one's got a baby so we're like
fully in the jungle at the moment so these guys
are as wild as they can be I'll put on screen
now what type of monkeys these guys are I'm not
too sure you can see as well their fur was like
really thick they've evolved to have this uh
thick fur to keep them warm you can see here
now as well the trees have also changed from pine
trees to more like rainforest trees I think that's
why we have seen the monkeys because this side
of it is a lot more tropical and it's uh lower
in altitude so different types of trees are
growing here so yeah it's really interesting
that I had just thought Bhutan was just covered
in pine trees but that's definitely not the case
I tell you what the beauty of this country is
just absolutely amazing we're driving through
these windy roads the road is nice and flat you
can hear the birds chirping cows on the side of
the road eating the grass keeping the grass down
so so lovely just stopped off here to this uh
little Fruit Stand but you can see out in here to
these rice patties in this little village we're
going to go up to this fruit stand here and see
what they have they got a little guard dog here
and uh we might try and buy some vegetables or
something hello how are you Z zampo wow what do
you have oh chips oh wow L okay this one is made
off of a rice flour and this come from Paka it's
a very famous we call it meu in our language and
it's like um snacks uh we eat with a tea and it's
very famous What's this called Dom domma okay I
I get uh two dma please thank you I really like
your store it's very nice you have a very lovely
place it's very nice yeah the view is very good
as well wow so yeah this is where this lady lives
her bed is here and this is where she does all of
her cooking cooking utensils and it's just a
little little Hut it's very nice see all made
out of wood so lovely and check out this this
view is absolutely amazing H imagine waking up
to that every day got the clothes line here the
simple life that's for sure hey nice meeting you
the locals here are so friendly such a nice little
little shop you know very basic but you know you
don't need much when you have a amazing view like
this she lives and works there very simple [Music]
life
just stopped on the side of the road to uh
get some fresh corn cooked up here on this
fire a lot of places doing it but apparently
this lady has opened All Season wow M smells
[Music]
good
so there you go that's how they
cook the uh cook the corn here
over the fire you can smell it smells
so fresh and so good I'm really excited
nothing like fresh corn cooked on an
open fire here in the mountains in
bhan that's very good this what village life is
all about so you can see I've got all of the wood
here 150 for two pieces so that's $3 so $150
each so simple here you know this reminds me
when I was in the uh rural villages in Nepal
had similar things like this obviously here
in Bhutan it's quite hard to earn a living
especially if you don't have any skills so
having a store like this on the side of the
road is great because tourists like us will
come and buy some fruit and vegetables and
water and Beetle nuts and everything so I
was just vlogging and my friend Kinley here who
I met the other night he's actually a subscriber
of the channel and toh randomly just drove past
it's the smallest so where are you going today
we are going to W right now my brother has a
soccer match so we are going to chat up them
so yeah awesome bro that's so good wow cool
cool cool amazing this is your father yeah
my dad Hello nice to meet you nice to meet you
sir nice to meet you and this is your brother
cous oh cousin cousin nice to meet you nice to
meet you well uh have a great day okay yeah and
hopefully we can meet up when we come back yes
see you by it was good seeing you byebye bye
bye wow how cool is that the most random crazy
right yeah wow Bhutan is such a small country
so you know she's offering this to us for free
yes thank you you're so kind welome thank you
wow oh so kind so we've just been offered some
more cucumber here for free with some spices on
it wow I'm loving bhan wow people here are
so kind they just gave this to us for free
like we only bought some corn and I just saw my
friend this is why I travel guys and I'm so glad
I can share these experiences with you to just
stop on the side of the road seeing my friend
be offered free food hello where else where else
do you get this in the world so because it's hot
now they're just fixing my gold to be like taken
down a bit this one okay oh nice that's so much
better so much better all this waste here is
going to be for the cows all the old lettuce
all the corn uh the corn outing wow very nice
you're so strong thank you thank you so much
you're so kind so yeah if you're in Bhutan come
to this shop so right now it's like the payment is
online system ah I see so this is our QR code scan
and pay yes awesome cool well everyone send money
to that account you'll be you'll be a millionaire
once this video goes viral what what makes her so
happy so she say she's telling that you know
if our kids are good like healthy and happy
it makes her happy wow that's awesome thank you
so much for being so kind I love the people here
[Music] so right now we're walking we're uh
not walking we're driving through the town
of Lisa what's the name of it so uh there's
two different types one we call it for the GI
same like this yes we call as a CO Soko yeah
so bigger one we call it a Chuchu Chuchu yes
we call it Chuchu like uh then we call it J J
Yes W then we call it as po as well wow so many
names wow and all of these are SOS yes wow so
related to our birth age I met the this one is
it this your biggest Soo yes wow it's very big
so this is you wow this is the rabbit so this is
according to my birth date and month and year this
is sopia this is yours yeah see wow nice mushroom
yeah nice but we can't eat this and so so that
people understand these are used as protectors for
the home right yes wow also like firstly we B keep
this things to bring power and also to protect
from the heavly spirit even like the person who
is feeling jealous for our business also yeah it
wow and you've like felt this working before yeah
sure wow that's amazing all right so this is also
like a protector and guider and helper right
yeah yeah okay thank you so much for sharing
it's very interesting people in the west might be
thinking what is going on right now but yeah this
is is what they believe which is really cool even
outside here you can see all on the houses they
have them here they have them as well so yeah
it's like a protector and many different many
different meanings it's really really amazing also
helps with uh fertility if you're having fertility
issues you should buy them and put them in your
house so amazing to experience different cultures
all around the world like just look at this
look at this oh wow look at this water so clear
so we're just in the beautiful rice fields at the
moment the irrigation system to feed all this rice
just comes naturally from the river and they've
built this all up and then once this is ready
they'll Harvest that and use that to make money
here in the village yeah all this land is just for
farming and then they have the village up there
for their homes we're just going to walk through
here to The Village on the other side where
we'll get picked up and then continue our journey
[Music]
so we're now in the beautiful town of Paka
and this place is stunning so we're at the
front of the Paka zone or what used to be the Paka
Fortress this Fortress here a lot of monks live in
here now and it's all controlled by the uh by
the government and by the monks so yeah super
fascinating isn't it so this Fortress is actually
on the corner of two rivers that meet up one is a
female River and the other one is a male River
now you might be thinking what is a female and
male River well the female river is a river that
flows very nice and slow not much current the male
river is very fast and aggressive and they meet to
form you know the baby I guess which would be the
the next river is the kunaka Zone Paka Fortress
so we've just came into the PT entrance now I'm
lost for words this is just magical look at these
horses right here just freely roaming next to the
Fortress okay so we're about to walk into the
zong right now I've had to put my go uh back
on so it's a sign of respect and if I didn't
have it then it would be okay but because it
was halfway down uh it's respectful to put it on
nicely yeah let's go in and check this [Music]
[Music]
out I tell you what this song is extremely
beautiful it's got lovely pink flowers up
here and lovely yellow and white flowers down
there you can hear the birds chirping so so
nice yeah so as you can see this building here
is very very nice so up here you can actually
see honey bees all growing off the side of the
zong here absolutely [Music] [Applause] [Music]
amazing
unfortunately we weren't allowed to film at that
zong but anyway it doesn't matter we're here at
this lovely campsite by the river and we're
actually going to be doing some rafting yeah
the white Ro rafting here in Bhutan probably
a first look at it I don't think that this
is on YouTube at all but first things first
we're going to have some lunch just [Music]
here
yeah how is it how is it did you find that
experience so good yeah that was your first
time White Water R yeah yeah I I I loved it we're
now walking to the suspension bridge uh but I have
to say the ban Countryside is absolutely beautiful
like along there when we're rafting there was wild
horses eating on the side we've even got a cow
here we have some dogs following us hello [Music]
dogs yeah as you can see stunning so
this is actually the male river that I
was talking about so when the female River
met and the male River met we went rafting
down the female River cuz it was a lot
quieter this bridge actually goes over
the male river right now we're going to go to
our home stay which is actually in a little
uh sort of local Village area so I can't
wait to show you guys that should be really
[Music] interesting
[Music]
H how are
you so we've just arrived at our beautiful home
stad so let's go in and check it out in the middle
of nowhere there's just forest all around us this
pomy grma Wow Fresh pomeg gmit tree whole leap
of other fruits too I think guava guava this is
guava as well yeah oranges more oranges I think
oh papaya oh you have a very lovely home let's
sit down oh it's been a long day guys a long
day oh they even got the mud house here in the
back this is exactly what I wanted a authentic
Homestay here in Bhutan look at this table so nice
eh this is what I want to have in our home one day
when we build in Nepal all natural like this eh
yes yeah so cool hello hey Kitty hey Kitty hey
Kitty already making friends so everything here
is handmade yes wow and then some all organic
yes so all of this is from the garden yes wow
that's insan this is why I came to bhan to try
stuff like this wow what a treat about to try
copsy which she has kindly made for us fresh
so yeah this is very fresh dip it in with the
tea so I've just got some mango here I've never
had this before in my life
so I'm going to give this A
Taste sort of a little bit
sweet but it's like a Savory
[Music]
dish they even have a amazing outdoor kitchen here
and the floor here is just so amazing they've got
the wooden fire here that heats up all the pots
for cooking so all of these stoves here are made
out of clay and that's what sort of keeps it
intact but after a while you can see it sort
of gets all cracked and broken so we're just
going for a little walk around here just having
a little look there's like neighbors and stuff
nearby they've got this whole Rice Field down
here this is the real Bhutan right here let me
tell you I've been told to put some long pants
and long sleeve on because apparently there's
this bug and if it bites you it gets itchier
and itchier and each here but um I haven't done
that because I can't be bothered so hopefully I
don't get bitten otherwise my silly mistake is
going to be really really bad they've got all
chilies and tomatoes here as well look at these
chilies so fresh we got red ones down there and
then a whole Greenhouse here and here we've
got all the beautiful Rice Terraces and then
up here looks to be a local house as well so
glad I can take you guys out to these rural
areas this is something that you don't often see
too much on YouTube because it's harder to get
to especially the home stay that we're staying
at so yeah we're extremely lucky today timble
oo smells strong it's like a spice or something
yes wow and it's from this tree here oh wow like
a scrub wow this yes wow so that's used as like a
natural scrub like a natural soap when you take a
shower they have everything here so resourceful
and this one is lemon orange orange and up here
they have more chili more chili here and then
here is punin and then up there is lemon so
yeah everything she cooked for us today was from
her garden so they're very very resourceful here
here all different types of uh medicine here it's
really really cool I love places like this out in
the jungle you know I really want to have my own
property one day grow all my own food have some
sheep have some chickens have some ducks maybe
even a few rabbits just a simple life you know
simple life is the best life I reckon away from
all of the nonsense in the city eventually I'd
love to build something like this any Village
video I love making isn't that right pussycat
isn't that right yeah I've been offered to come
and milk the cow so we're going to go and do that
so I've never ever in my life I don't think uh
milked a cow before so this will be really really
interesting in Nepal uh cow is a very sacred
animal so they have Buffalo milk rather than cow
milk but here here the um the cows are are used
for farming so it should be really interesting so
why is there water in there uh to wash the milk oh
I see I see okay nice I asked you know there's a
lot of cows on the side of the road can someone
just grab a cow and take it as their own cuz no
one would know and they said no you're not allowed
to do that uh it's against the rules avocado avoc
avocado oh wow look oh avocado beautiful wow and
this is your beautiful cow does the cow have a
name junko junko we've came to milk you she's
washing the utterers of the cow to clean it
off ah there we go there we
go wow so much amazing and you're
holding back the tail uh if we have
like C then it gives 10 lit of milk
10 L and how much lers would this be
now she gives only two to three two
to three that's butter is it yeah
okay okay sorry or ah wow my first
time milking a cow wow amazing
yeah yeah the professionals okay okay
I'll try again so I got to get up way
more not that good okay I'll let the professional
so after you milk do you have to boil this or it's
okay you can drink yeah we usually boil and
and then okay amazing and because uh you guys
grow a lot of stuff here how often do you have
to go to town to buy things I think yeah okay
doesn't go much doesn't go in a month or once or
twice once a month once or twice a month wow so
they're so resourceful here they're only going
to town once or twice a month cuz most of their
stuff just comes from the land it's really amazing
isn't it you can see how full her UTS are though
but I could imagine when she's uh has a cal there
would be even more full like 10 L good girl she is
and they're keeping her distracted by feeding
her some brand new grass and this keeps her
distracted and so she doesn't kick and you know
get all annoyed she's way too much focus on the
green grass here she's hogging down aren't you
girl hey aren't you yes we've also got the dog
and the cat to come and watch the cow being milked
the whole family is here for this occasion so in
Australia we have machines that milk the cows
yeah yeah but I think the machines hurt them I
think this is a better natural way so the cow here
isn't even tied up so it could just walk off and
be free but it knows it's Ono and it knows that
it's going to be milked every day it knows that
it's going to be taken care for so that it doesn't
run off unlike in Australia we put our cows in a
massive padic and fence see this cow could just go
into the rice fields and never come back but just
decides to stay it's really amazing isn't it it's
like that with a lot of animals especially here in
South Asia it's really common wow all done okay
how much did we get quite a lot about 2 L and so
will this milk be used for butter or for drinking
or everything cheese butter and for drinking also
wow awesome so this is an old well but now it's
dried up so they they used to drink out of there
because of the road the road stopped it yeah ah
right now she's just chopping up all grass here
for the cow and it's going she's going to cook it
in here and give it a mixture of different types
of food different types of warm food including
this as well it's a supplement diet so rather
than just grass this will be this is a different
type of grass and then you've got the pellets in
here as well and then by doing this it'll keep
the cow's Health really good and also help her
to produce really good Rich healthy milk so
yeah and one thing I'll just show you in here
this is what they use to make butter and cheese
uh this machine here and this will Stir It and
uh do its thing and then in here this is the uh
food for the cow so yeah oh and they even have a
old weaving machine in here too this property
is very old I wonder how long she's been here
traditional banese dinner looks like and how they
prepare the food actually cooking here right now
is there rice in this one okay so
they've got soup in here also frying
up some onions and we've got tomato as
well so yeah this is really really cool
and we've also got some Vines here as
well chili and beans it's all Happening
Here we got our local rice wine with
our egg inside as well rice wine with
egg it's extremely strong stronger than vodka I
don't know what percentage but a lot tastes like
[Music] 50% this butter and cheese made here
only butter and cheese from the cow yes wow
that's amazing so the cow that we milked that's
the same butter and cheese okay so dinner has
now been served got all different types of food
here okay so we've got our food here check this
out doesn't that look good so we've got chicken
we've got a mushroom Curry we've got beans' got
everything so um I think I'm going to use my hands
use the um do the local way so let's dig in shall
we oh wow oh my gosh wow so I just finished
off my meal there I'm so full and I've brought
out more dessert I don't know how I'm going
to finish this but uh yeah I'm going to say
good night to you guys there and uh we'll see you
tomorrow morning sure see you then bye bye good
[Applause] night welcome back to another
beautiful morning here in Bhutan so this
morning we woke up and we had some coffee and
also a lovely breakfast with cheese omelette
rice capsican and tomato and everything from that
was from this Garden here the eggs the cheese was
from the milk from the cow and the tomato and
the capsican was from the garden I also tried
some rare fruit that I've never had and also a
tree tomato that's right a tomato that grows on
a tree I've never had that before and then this
morning I'mma here who lives in the house she
helped me dress my go so uh yeah I'm wearing
that right now and Sophia got dressed in her
Kira and then we also did a temple ceremony in
the house now there's a whole Shrine dedicated
in a room in the house here and uh we got
to light some incense and light a candle
as well so yeah this morning has been really
amazing I've really enjoyed my time here in the
[Music]
village so now we're just walking to
see the hot Stone bar I didn't even
know that they had here so it'll
be interesting to see wow look at
this this is so pretty I'm going to miss this
place I tell you what it would be so good if we
were here for a few more nights but we have
the rest of bhan to [Music] explore [Music]
just here we have actual lle wow this is a cross
between like a tadpole and a Frog Okay so we've
now reached down to where the hot stone baths are
oh my gosh if this isn't being one with nature I
don't know what is wow so we've got the fire pit
here the stones get heated up and then they get
put into these C Stone bar I would have loved to
have a go in this but unfortunately we don't have
enough time for today yeah this hose here as you
can see fills up from the river and all of this
wood here is the wood that is collected to then
burn the fire so the hot stone baths here in bhan
what they do is they heat up the Rocks the Rocks
then heat up the water and they put a whole heap
of different herbs and different like um holistic
medicines in the water and it's really good for
your toxins in the skin and then yeah you can see
here it's rained a lot last night so the water's
quite brown but I would say normally this would
be very clear water here so also this morning
we were shown photos of how the oil that is used
in the cooking is created and it's actually from
the seeds in this tree behind me the seeds get
roasted and then pressed out all the oil gets
pressed out so literally everything that they use
cook here is from all around us even down to the
oil so this machine here behind me actually
Shucks the rice so removes the rice from the
outer layout and then now that's perfectly good
rice to cook and eat so cool wow you look pretty
this morning thank you you ready to go yeah yeah
excited yay let's go cut in shella thank you so
much your hospitality has been amazing we've
had a great great time your home stay is very
beautiful
good you're so kind thank you so much thank
[Laughter] you byebye bye see you
bye you sad yeah I am that was so nice right yeah
[Music] bye so I just felt the love of grandmother
and I couldn't see my mom's mom because she
died when my mom was pregnant and I couldn't
spend my time with my dad's mom because she died
of cancer and I just felt the love of grandma she
was lovely wasn't she she's so kind She's always
feeding us and always making sure we're okay
and hugging us even though she couldn't speak
English yeah that's a warm I got warm feeling
yeah I agree she's so lovely so lovely going
to miss Elma I love youma if you're watching
we love [Music] you so we've just stopped off to
this beautiful Viewpoint look at this absolutely
[Music]
stunning
W okay so we're now 3,250 m above sea level and
this is a electric taxi that's cool so this uh
area is called no well I hope I'm saying that
right apologies if not so yeah they've got a
lovely stuper up here and a amazing prayer Flags
now from what I've experienced on my travels a
lot of monasteries and sters and temples are
at the top of a big hill and I think it's due
to um sort of like a spiritual aspect you know
the top of a hill has a amazing view now this
is open so I believe wo lot of cow poo here
so yeah I believe we can come in they have uh
a lot of banese riding here I say that these
are some type of montras or something if you
know let me know in the comments and yeah got
a lovely stuper up here so this uh this stoer
is a little bit uh worse for wear a little
bit needs a little bit of Maintenance but
it's still really beautiful we've got the uh
Buddha reincarnation up there yeah I hope that
you're enjoying this series in Bhutan if
you are leave a like and a subscribe and
your comments are always amazing uh I love
reading your comments so please comment and
let me know what you want to see out of
this series and where I should [Laughter]
go so we've now arrived in the beautiful
town of gke and we're now in front of the
monk Monastery here and as you can see
behind me they're actually been washing
their monk robes let's go in and uh see this
Monastery wow this Monastery is stunning so
no problems filming in this one unlike
the one we had the other day because this
one is privately owned uh but yeah you
can see all the wooden architecture up
here [Music] [Applause]
[Applause]
yeah
so this Monastery is really lovely there's like uh
local tourists here that have came from far away
to come here and there's also locals here sitting
down and eating and then there's also monks that
live here as well so beautiful and stunning
this is what a real raw Monastery looks like
you know one that hasn't been overc consumed
by uh consumerism and money this is the real
deal this is a real monk Monastery here hello
so uh yeah this is really lovely hello so I'm
just going for a walk around this Monastery now
it's really really lovely Monastery my guide's
actually talking to one of the monks here I
think she knows him so I thought I'll just go
around by myself this is really really lovely
so authentic so all the monks live around this
side of the monastery so you can see their uh
their homes and their beds and stuff in there
and the monks here speak fairly good English I
was just had a small chat to one of the young
boys I didn't get it on camera unfortunately yeah
as you can see they've got the CP and everything
out here and they're washing everything and this
is all their living quarters so yeah it's really
lovely and if they're not wearing red they're
wearing gold or yellow right now this um Temple
is uh run by you know look after by the ninth
Reincarnation of gandi we call it him as a g
he's like a guru yes okay and what's today today's
Friday so they're they're not studying today uh no
they have a like a Puja ritual going on a Puja
so what's that a Puja is like kind of like you
know the M they will create and perform a ritual
like reading out the mantras oh I see I see Hello
they can either choose to uh to continue to be
a monk or to leave and uh go into the outside
world hello how are you hi that's good the kids
here are so nice so friendly hello how are you
good he fine they're all so nervous I don't think
they get many uh foreigners come in with a camera
probably not many especially here in Bhutan if
it was in Thailand it would be a different story
but bhan not many foreigners come here so they're
probably not used to it what's he doing um [Music]
so there's a hor so they he's going to like you
know like a coffee to make
a coffee oh hello can I play
yeah can I play
[Laughter]
yeah
[Music] the road taking us to lunch
is a little bit bumpy it's fun though
hey you ready for lunch yeah wow
lunch with a review it's going
to be good beautiful I'm really
hungry too are you hungry [Music]
y just came into this place here for lunch
and as you can see the view is so nice I'm
really really excited to eat so because it's
low season we're actually the only ones here
in the restaurant which is actually it's
quite nice because you sort of get all the
attention to yourself so we just got our food
so we've got rice looks to be fish some type
of soup here fresh vegetables and some type of
potato uh fries as well okay let's give this a
try wow every meal I've had in Bhutan has been So
Fresh So Fresh still haven't had a bad
meal yet let's try some of this soup
so creamy so lovely we're going to enjoy this
and fill [Music] up okay so are just leaving
the beautiful hotel and restaurant here now we're
going to see the black neck cranes I'm so excited
for this so I actually got it wrong we're not
going to see the cranes just yet we're going
for a hike all the way on the other side of this
Valley just a quick little hike I think I'm not
too sure how long we'll go for uh but then we'll
go and see the black neck cranes got a little bit
of a traffic jam in Bhutan it's not cars that make
up the traffic it's cows and horses so what's are
these flags and these streer M ster yeah so it all
related to Dharma so if you book like uh like in
deeper so it's like different stoer has different
meaning ah I say you know I'm moments like these
you just begin to realize where you are in this
world and uh yeah it's so lucky sometimes when
you travel as much as me sometimes things become
normal but when you eventually just look back
you're like wow this is where I am right now and
I'm so blessed to be able to share this with you
guys and uh show you an insight into Bhutan and
also my travels from all around the world because
you know I'm extremely blessed to be able to do
this and sometimes when I'm so focused on filming
filming and all of this you actually don't see
the beauty around you but uh it's important to
when the camera is put down to really embrace it
you [Music] know one thing that I thought I would
touch on whil we're on this hike is to talk about
how marriages are done here in Bhutan now there's
actually no marriage ceremony at all uh when
a couple wants to get married they essentially
just live together and that's it as of recently
there was no marriage certificates nothing like
that there was no paperwork no nothing people
wouldn't even go out to dinner to celebrate
they would just live together and that was it
very strange considering their neighbor India
and Nepal they love marriages India weddings
can go on for 3 4 days uh Napo weddings 2 days
absolutely crazy isn't it how different it is
right next to the border of these countries
that are renowned for big beautiful weddings
but yeah that's their culture here and uh
they've preserved it which is wonderful at the
river and before we get in the car I actually
want to drink some of this water because this
looks super Super Fresh let's give this a try
you can see straight through and it's running
but where to scoop it up is the problem let's
say
okay why not it's running water it's fine my
stomach is iron it is it is I didn't even I
won't it'll be fine I drank from River every
day in village in Nepal let's see if I get sick
I raise my hand i'm wrong you know usually when
we are with guest we don't allow them to drink
the spring water because like for us we have been
grown up that's because they are very rich guests
from their little home in their first world
country and have never traveled I am different
okay I'm a I'm a traveler not a holiday maker
what did you collect along the way that because
I'm wearing white oh nice that's nice looks
good yeah thank you so we have now arrived at
the black neck crane Center hopefully we see some
black neck cranes and also learn a lot more about
these amazing animals I believe there's a lot of
interesting things about these guys how's it look
how's it going like a crane wow black neck crane
nice wow so we're about to go up to the black neck
cranes now I thought that this one over here was
a statue but it actually started moving so yeah
this is what black neck crane looks like there
you go there's a close-up wall he's looking at
me so there you go there's a Hands-On look at the
black neck crane yeah so it's quite a shame that
they're in a cage but it is for reason because uh
for whatever reason they are a little bit sick and
they seem relatively happy like the cage is pretty
big just for the two of them but yeah a little bit
of information about these guys so in the winter
they fill up this Valley there's heaps of them
right and then when it hits summer they fly to
Tibet now when they fly to Tibet they actually
stop over in the monastery that we visited today
and circle three times around the monastery then
head to Tibet when they come back they do the
exact same thing believe it or not that's what
I've been told so that sounds really amazing
so unfortunately these guys here couldn't go
to Tibet isn't it amazing how animals can just
cross borders into a different country without
a passport like obviously it'd be silly if they
had a passport but they're like so free aren't
they so we're just driving back to the hotel but
we've just stopped off here at this uh little yak
yak store and there's uh there's cows on the
road and they sell Yak product here how are
you you're good nice to meet you and I say that
they live here as well cuz they've got a little
kitchen in here too and they probably lay out the
uh lay out the bed at night time when uh all the
tourists have gone yeah look they have these Yak
bags as well so this is just dyed yak wool here
feels really really nice too there's all flies
over it as well shows how fresh it is isn't it
find anything you like everything see where cute
wow that is nice is that bamboo yeah I think yeah
lovely so they've got cheese here as well and some
butter probably made out of yak milk or milk from
the cow really really nice up here in the mountain
they've also got lovely hand weav carpet here as
well big yuck tail and just some raw Yak skin
here as well so you can see this is the skin
part and this is all the wool and they they skin
this straight off the yak crazy so the skin do
they wait until the yak dies from natural causes
no means when they die only oh when they die yes
they are like you know Ys are their like family
to them they she was very surprised she was like
s s me no no no no she was very surprised I see
yeah so so that's good uh in Bhutan you you know
allow to kill animals so they only use the yak
skin once the animal has passed which is good
it's uh it's sustainable that way isn't it so
yeah really fascinating this little Hut on the
side of the road selling uh Yak products from the
milk yes from the milk oh wow amazing yeah okay
thank
you really hard it's softer comparing to other
one you just need to soak it in your she's got
it interesting so you just bought this uh Yak
blanket Y and it's from baby yak's wool yes shav
off the yak and it was handmade yeah for $1,500
which is about $30 mm such a good price for what
you get one thing that blows my mind about bhan
is how far away all the houses are in the most
remote places it's crazy like everywhere you look
there's always little houses dotted everywhere and
it would just it'd be so hard to get into the main
Town they'd be driving and walking and everything
it's like it's so crazy just the way that they
build around here is insane like you wouldn't
be going into town every day because you live so
far away from everything it's like so hard to get
to so we're just buying some snacks here for
the children at the Eco Lodge uh for three
bags of chips two drinks and some Beetle nut
as well for the owner so we've now arrived at
the beautiful EOL large hello sir how are
you I'm good sir nice to meet you too sir
your place is very lovely thank you very much
I love all the wood just a small Lodge in the
countryside so just basic one sir it took us
so long climbing up the mountains but I think
it's all going to be worth it but uh climbing
from down to up is like a discotex like this
beautiful wow basic no it's very good wow I would
say that this is luxury look at the cute little
tables and chairs big bed oh wow lovely site
yeah it's lovely big shower wow awesome this
is a lovely room wow look at this food oh my
God so after having a lovely night's rest at
the Eco Lodge We rise early to go and see
the monks in the monastery just in front of
our room little did we know that this would be
the start of a beautiful and magical day ahead
this was probably one of my most favorite days
in Bhutan and you'll see why I simply fell in
love so this is the one of the teachers here and
he teaches the zonka language and I asked him do
you like your job and he said yes because he
loves to teach the young kids and the young
minds of today it's very rewarding and as you
could imagine it would be so yeah very cool so
you can still hear the kids going so they're also
taught uh English and the uh English alphabet and
also counting in English uh once a week one of the
teachers from the school that we're going to visit
today actually comes here once a week so they can
have a basic understanding of of English which is
really practical in today's society especially
when visitors Like Us come and visit and we say
how are you then they know to say I'm fine and
just very basic English so it's very good for
[Applause]
them okay so we're just walking into the
monastery now the little monk just before
opened up the uh door for us to come in so let's
have a look beautiful wow this is really amazing
so this is on the side of the mountain and
as you can see out these windows we've got
a view so beautiful so it would be amazing to
sit here and meditate and then also have the
view out here have all the different teachings
and everything on the walls I asked if they're
actually praying to Buddha and the answer is
yes which I get different answers everywhere
I go to different countries when I went
to Napal they weren't actually praying to
Buddha the Buddha statue was more there to
remind them to reach Enlightenment so I'm
still a little bit confused there's different
dominations of Buddhism all around the world so
different people believe different things so
yeah if you know more about this let me know
in the comments it'd be interesting to hear
your thoughts oh they have a soccer field
down here too yes it's always fun as well prayer
school and fun so good good tree elements I like
[Applause] [Music]
that so right now we're just uh walking to the
owner's uh the owner's house of the Eco Lodge
so he doesn't actually stay at the Eco Lodge
he has his own house here so we're going to
go and see what that looks like I've also got a
cow down there and yeah really really big house
really lovely beautiful big old traditional
house here and then we've got another much
older house which I think has been turned into
a garden shed or something made from bricks and
mud so beautiful oh loveely his mother and his
father Hello nice to meet you nice to meet you
Hello nice to meet you hello dog oh and a cat
hello cat meow me and I've got pumpkin growing
here too and then another garden shed as well ah
beautiful chickens they got the firewood here also
the basket for firewood collection all different
building materials as well such a lovely home so
we've just been invited inside take our shoes off
first it's very hot today so we're going up these
stairs for/ ladder beautiful artwork here on the
walls I love this in bhan they really love all
the color here got little kids you're watching
TV yes yeah they've got some beautiful family
photos here look at the uncle look at him wow
yeah so we're just going into the other part
of the house now so this looks like also a
sleeping area too and the shrine beautiful
shine here such a lovely house and look at the
window beautiful view I've got all the mattresses
here when they sleep very lovely what's what's
your name what's your name name is wow nice to
meet you old wooden floors here big slats of
Timber so beautiful over time with the house
moving it's a little bit unlevel it just adds to
that authentic experience of the house we've got
the lovely roof here too Beau what's your name
you're beautiful so cute you're watching Peppa
Pig Peppa Pig no matter where in the world Peppa
Pig is everywhere she's been to Bangkok she's also
been to Nepal all these Family Photos uh on their
travels so this is definitely Bangkok just there
so this as well is where they burn all of their
rubbish because there's no rubbish collection
out here so they have a pit here a nice pit to uh
do that so the rubbish doesn't fly everywhere and
go out uh Amma there she is actually 73 73 years
old she can still hear very good still see very
good walks around working in the field Okay
so we've just came up now for breakfast yeah
it was really nice actually just exploring
before breakfast and now we're going to eat
and then after that we'll get in the car drive
about 10 20 minutes to the school wow thank you
[Music] so right now we're going past a very
very old house ruin here and we've got a old
house as well but this one's pretty much
collapsed so yeah very interesting this is
very very very old just made from Pure mud and
Stones we've got a beautiful horse here hello
horse K Okay so we've just arrived at the gaso
primary school hello everyone hi my name is Jack
I from Australia and today I am your teacher
I'm just joking your uh principal here is so
kind to let us come in and see your classroom
so uh yeah I I am a YouTuber so you will all
be on YouTube please sit Down's there how is our
country how is your country your country is very
nice one thing I love about your country
is uh how environmentally friendly it is
70% of your country is covered in trades your
people take very good care of your environment
[Applause] can I have your ch's name oh yes my
Channel's name it's been a while since I've done
[Music]
this Jack to that's my channel name
do you write our food yes yeah I love
your food it's uh very wholesome and
healthy I've been to other countries
where food is not healthy but here in
Bhutan the food is very healthy I like
[Applause] it like you have heard Alan is a g&
country so do you think that our people are happy
I think your people are very happy based on their
smiling faces they are very very happy awesome
okay thank you amazing so cool I didn't think
I'd be teing a class today so now we're moving
into the IT class let's go hello students how
are you so the King has set up all of this in
the classrooms and paid for all of this it's so
amazing to see here so even the King has set up
coding for kids which you know is so important
these days so kids in Bhutan are learning coding
which is amazing very good so every month uh Code
Monkey requires a subscription fee and the king is
also paying for that J are having really like
opportunities where they can explore it's all
the CR goes to our King the king's doing a lot
of good work it's good to say wow amazing does
anyone have any questions questions you yeah you
have questions can you talk about your countries
my country my country is Australia put your hand
up if you know Australia Australia know put your
hand raise your hand a deal to your friend dead
I am the shortest principal in bhan okay I got I
got that on film so I'll put that in I want
thank you so much thank you still have some
children who wants to take a autograph okay
autograph wow it's like on famous autograph
okay this is the first time I've done this
okay my handwriting isn't that good okay I'll
just use this one pen okay and then [Music]
and Sophia too wow this is what a school in
rural Bhutan looks like so amazing my name is
R sh I'm from BH and I like asalia I want to go
aalia hope de wow amazing thank you sir thank
you okay thank you bye bye bye thank you bye
wow lovely students see you thank you so much
again thank you thank you very much sir thank
you oh what an experience I think maybe that
was the best experience in Bhutan so far my
best experience in Bhutan wow my heart is
just filled with love at the moment oh I
just feel so humble and um and thankful that
we were able to visit that school and to see
the computers and the coding these kids are
very very smart it's very amazing incredibly
beautiful you sh one of the biggest rooms we
have had in Bhutan so far and just before we
take a tour I just want to show you that all
of this Garden here is used in the cooking of
the restaurant here these fresh apples here we
can pick right now and eat one but we actually
already have some inside so let's go in and check
it out some amazing apples here some mangoes as
well and also a bottle of Shevon blanc no I'm
just joking what is this called raven red wine
amazing a lovely bathtub here with a big shower
shampoo conditioner wood up here the beams are
made out of Cypress it really smells really really
good we come through here seating area just here
through here we've got a lovely little mini bar
and a bottle of water that isn't in plastic this
hotel does not use any plastic at all none just
glass it's amazing lovely little mini bar fridge
and then in here is the second bathroom with
a toilet and also a lovely shower as well so
yeah how cool is this guys to be in a apartment
like this is absolutely stunning so yeah we're
very very blessed I'll leave the link in the
description if you're interested in staying
in this place as today comes to be our final day
in Bhutan we take a broader look at Ban's place
in the world this tiny country has managed to
preserve its Traditions while sandwich between
two major neighbors China and India brutan
grapples with the forces of globalization
yet will it manage its sustainable approach
focused on on gross national happiness well
let's find out Da restaurant bhutan's most
extremely local restaurant I can guarantee
you that a tourist has never ever been here
[Music] hello oh I think the microwave just blew
up so yeah welcome to today's Vlog uh a very
very local experience so yeah enjoy okay that's
CH they've got fried chili they've got Cham in
which one nimi what's that nimi is a hard bread
so we're going to get some nimi and also some tea
as well we've been allowed to film their kitchen
here hello sir please come you're right it's very
crowded here it's nice and busy very low door wow
very nice kitchen eggum rambro very lovely all
made out of wood pops and pans here very very
nice very old nice fridge and uh yeah this is what
a Local Kitchen extremely local looks like here in
Bhutan Okay so we've just been given our Chia here
so it's very very hot pretty good really really
nice we also got what what do what we call n
nimy so we've got an O very flaky I didn't expect
that really good uh for all of that for four teas
and the uh the snack that we had there so that's
two $2 very good thank you so much so we've just
we've just stopped on the side of the road and
they're are just doing archery here as as a sport
it's very popular here they're very very good at
it I think something's on fire they're burning
the uh the incense burning the plane just here
W so cool to be able to get this local
experience here you won't see this much
on YouTube hello how are you fine that's good
see yeah they're burning pine leaves here and
hopefully that will cause the rain to stop
so I'm going to go back walk back over now
because if I wait on that side then the arrows
will start flying and then I might get hit so
it's best to be over here you you can see here
this is the uh this is the case that they keep
their bow and arrow in so yeah I wonder how
expensive these are cost 30,000 before it
used to cost like 7,000 8,000 but now it is like
30,000 so much any any any dealer it's handmade
yes yeah wow amazing 30,000 for one of those
bows I'll put up the price just here very very
expensive so we're just you know local
supermarket this what a supermarket looks
like in Bhutan and we're buying some beer
to have with our lunch this whole bottle
of whiskey is only $6 look at the size of
it bhan is very famous for their very cheap
alcohol as you can see this one $6 this one $7
wine uh $3 Black Mountain whiskey $3 crazy not
many people know this about Bhutan but yeah the
alcohol here is extremely cheap and affordable
uh because it's locally produced here and
they produce it very cheaply this is the
first like store I've seen in bhan that has
like everything like a supermarket thank you
sir you thank you okay so we've just came into
uh where we're going to have lunch today and
they're just setting up a table for us here
really really lovely spot this can look all
over the uh town here in parro so yeah really
nice I'm excited to see what we're going to
[Music] eat okay so we just finished up there
that was really tasty right really really good
food the pasta was so nice I never get to have
pasta much these days but having it here was
really good my mom used to cook pasta at one
once every week and I've missed it so yeah
it was good to have pasta g day and good morning
guys as you can see behind us it is very dark it
is currently 4:30 a.m. and we about to head
to the airport to fly back to Nepal I don't
want to go Sophia doesn't want to go I don't
want to go it's really sad um unfortunately
today is our very last day and we have to
say goodbye to senu and sent you our guide
and dummer our driver so yeah it's going to be
sad because I've been like our family so come
along with us and uh yeah let's say goodbye and
this is our gift for our driver and guide we've
got some apples some red wine some beer and a
feedback let off so yeah it should be nice to
give that to them because theyve been so kind
taking us around so well that concludes our
journey through the captivating Kingdom of
Bhutan a truly magical experience from the
thrilling Heights to the spiritual depths this is
a trip that will stay in our minds for myself and
my girlfriend forever I hope you now also have a
new appreciation of this country and that you'll
be able to visit for yourself someday see you
in the next episode and as always keep it real
cheers
[Music]
Prett that